Student Handbooks; Collection ua936
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Student Handbook Collection
1904-1995
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany
ua936
1.16 cubic ft.
Collection is made up of the student handbooks issued by the student association.
Administrative History
The first student handbook was published in 1904 for incoming student of the New York State Normal College. It contained basic information introducing the institution to new students. It had lists of the members of class government as well as the student societies on campus. Since it was published by the Young Women's Christian Association it also contained information on the local chapter.
It developed over the years expanding the information included in each succeeding volume. Into the 1950s and 1960s the handbook grew with the student population. It included information like every single campus group, off campus activities like dance halls, bars, and movie theaters, giving a full description of college life. This continued until 1997 when the handbook ceased publication.
Scope and Contents
This collection holds the complete run of the student handbooks. It was published for freshman students who were coming into the university. They hold information related to student life on and off campus. They reveal a good picture of event s and groups run by students as well as how the university expanded greatly when the uptown campus was built.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is arranged in chronological order.
Acquisition Information
All items in this manuscript group were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Handbooks, vade-mecums, etc.; College Freshman; College Students; UAlbany Reference Collections
- Student Handbook, 1904 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1906 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1907 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1908 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1914 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Student Handbook, 1915 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Student Handbook, 1917 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Student Handbook, 1918 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Student Handbook, 1919 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Student Handbook, 1920 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Student Handbook, 1921 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Student Handbook, 1922 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Student Handbook, 1923 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Student Handbook, 1924 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Student Handbook, 1925 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Student Handbook, 1926 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Student Handbook, 1927 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Student Handbook, 1928 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Student Handbook, 1929 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Student Handbook, 1930 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)
- Student Handbook, 1931 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)
- Student Handbook, 1932 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)
- Student Handbook, 1933 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 8)
- Student Handbook, 1934 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 8)
- Student Handbook, 1935 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 8)
- Student Handbook, 1936 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 9)
- Student Handbook, 1937 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 9)
- Student Handbook, 1938 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 9)
- Student Handbook, 1938 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 10)
- Student Handbook, 1939 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 10)
- Student Handbook, 1940 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 10)
- Student Handbook, 1941 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 11)
- Student Handbook, 1942 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 11)
- Student Handbook, 1943 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 11)
- Student Handbook, 1944 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 12)
- Student Handbook, 1945 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 12)
- Student Handbook, 1946 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 12)
- Student Handbook, 1947 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 13)
- Student Handbook, 1948 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 13)
- Student Handbook, 1949 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 13)
- Student Handbook, 1950 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 14)
- Student Handbook, 1951 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 14)
- Student Handbook, 1952 (Box 1 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 14)
- Student Handbook, 1953 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1954 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1955 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1956 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Student Handbook, 1957 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Student Handbook, 1958 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Student Handbook, 1959 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Student Handbook, 1960 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Student Handbook, 1961 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Student Handbook, 1962 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1963 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1964 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1965 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1966 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1967 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1968 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1969 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 8)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1970 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 8)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1971 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 9)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1972 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 9)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1973 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 10)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1974 (Box 2 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 10)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1975 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1976 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1977 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1978 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1979 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1981 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1987 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)
- Student Handbook, 1989 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 8)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1989 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 9)
- Student Handbook, 1990 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 10)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1990 (Box 3 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 11)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1991 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 1)
- Student Handbook, 1991 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 2)
- Campus Viewpoint, 1992 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 3)
- Student Guide, 1993 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 4)
- Student Handbook, 1994 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 5)
- Student Association Group Guide, 1995 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 6)
- Student Handbook, 1995 (Box 4 (Student Handbook Collection), Folder 7)